Guide to the Robert Abercrombie Lovett Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert Abercrombie Lovett papers
1919-1986
MS 1617
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
14
(35 boxes)
The papers consist of Robert Lovett's personal correspondence, speeches, photographs, and memorabilia, which date from the periods of his adult life when he was not serving in government. The papers document Lovett's personal friendships with business, military, and government associates and pioneer aviators from the Yale Naval Air Unit. The correspondence includes many exchanges with scholars doing historical research on World War II and the Truman administration. The papers highlight Lovett's contributions to philanthropic organizations as well as the many honors accorded to him. The papers do not include files kept by Lovett as a partner of Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.
Lovett, Robert A. (Robert Abercrombie), 1895-1986
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Some Levitt family correspondence is restricted until 2016. Some correspondence with Marshall N. Carter, Marshall S. Carter, and Preot Carter will remain restricted until declassified by the National Archives and Records Administration of the United States.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Christopher L. Brown, David S. Brown, Jr., Robert L. Brown, Evelyn deHaven Lovett, Robert A. Lovett II, Virginia Lovett, and Adele Q. Brown Nelken, 1991 and 1993.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence and topical files, 1919-1986. II. Writings, 1936-1981.
Scope and Contents
The Robert Abercrombie Lovett Papers consist of correspondence, speeches, photographs, and memorabilia, most of which date from the periods in Robert Lovett's adult life when he was not serving in government. The papers document Lovett's personal friendships and highlight Lovett's contributions to various philanthropic organizations as well as the many honors and distinctions accorded to him for his long years of service. Some reflection on this service will also be found in Lovett's later correspondence with scholars and in his speeches and writings.
Christopher L. Brown, David S. Brown, Jr., Robert L. Brown, Evelyn deHaven Lovett, Robert A. Lovett II, Virginia Lovett, and Adele Q. Brown Nelken donated their grandfather's and father-in-law's papers to the Yale University Library in 1991 and 1993. The papers are now arranged in two series: I. Correspondence and Topical Files and II. Writings. Correspondence and Topical Files is the larger of the two series.
The files in Correspondence and Topical Files contain both material by and about an individual or subject, including letters, clippings, speeches, photographs, financial records, and printed material. The series also includes information on the genealogies of the Abercrombie and Lovett families. There are several folders for Robert Scott Lovett containing tributes and messages of condolence on his death. Arranged in the files under Robert A. Lovett are citations, medals, medical records, and volumes of congratulatory messages. These volumes may contain letters from individuals the remainder of whose correspondence is filed under their personal name. Similar congratulatory correspondence can be found under the name of the award or event such as Presidential Medal of Freedom or Sylvanus Thayer Award.
Lovett's most frequent correspondents include close business, military, and government associates. The correspondence is between old friends and marks anniversaries, other celebrations, honors, and awards. There are often discussions of family members, vacations, and finances.
The series includes files for every president from Harry S. Truman through Lyndon B. Johnson. The series also includes exchanges with personal friends such as the poet and playwright Archibald MacLeish, the author John O'Hara, and Swedish banker Marcus Wallenburg. Prominent among Lovett's correspondents are public servants from the Roosevelt and Truman administrations such as Dean Acheson, George C. Marshall, John J. McCloy, and Anna M. Rosenberg. There are a few letters from James V. Forrestal in the Forrestal file which also includes memorials to and writings about him. More material on Forrestal is in the files of Herbert Elliston and Marx Leva. Individuals who worked for and admired George C. Marshall, such as C. J. George, Marshall S. Carter, and Forrest Pogue are among Lovett's frequent correspondents. There are also voluminous files, including minutes of meetings, on the George C. Marshall Research Foundation for which Lovett served as chairman of the board.
Lovett's continuing interest in military affairs, particularly military aviation, is evident in correspondence and in speeches and congressional testimony found in Series II, Writings. Correspondents include former members of the Yale Unit such as Trubee Davison and Artemus Gates, as well as former Brown Brothers partner and senator Prescott Bush, Laurus Norstad, the retired Supreme Allied Commander of Europe, and columnist Ira Eaker.
Some reflection by Lovett on his years of public service can be found in correspondence with writers and scholars like: Sydney Bailey and John Osborne on the Middle East; Calvin Christman on Ferdinand Eberstadt and the War Production Board; Daryl Hudson on the Vandenburg Resolution and the North Atlantic Treaty; and Jan H. Kalicki on the Sino-American crises in the 1950s. Other reminiscences can be found in Series II in oral history transcripts.
Since Lovett did not remove any papers he generated in his positions at the United States War Department, State Department, and Defense Department, these files are presumably now in the custody of the National Archives. Similarly, since Lovett did not retain his working files as a partner in Brown Brothers, Harriman, & Co., these files should remain with the company's records.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Abercrombie Lovett was born in Huntsville, Texas, on September 14, 1895, the son of Robert Scott and Lavinia Chilton Abercrombie Lovett. The senior Lovett served as general counsel to E. H. Harriman's Union Pacific Railroad. When he became a director of the railroad in 1909, he moved his family to Locust Valley, New York.
Lovett graduated from the Hill School in Pottstown, Pennsylvania, in 1914. He entered Yale University with the class of 1918 and was a junior when America entered World War I. Leaving school to join the war effort, he became an ensign and helped organize the first Yale Unit of Naval Aircraft. After receiving pilot's training, he flew many sorties over Germany and Belgium. He was discharged from the navy in 1919 as a lieutenant commander. On April 19, 1919, he married his Long Island neighbor, Adele Quarterly Brown, daughter of James Brown, the senior partner of the investment firm of Brown Brothers.
After completing his bachelor's degree at Yale, Lovett studied law and business at Harvard University. In 1921, he returned to New York, where he worked briefly as a clerk in a New York bank. Lovett then was given a position at Brown Brothers. He became a firm partner in 1926 and in the same year was elected a director of the Union Pacific Railroad and several of its subsidiaries. Not long after he effected the merger of the Harriman investment interests into what became the banking concern of Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.
Through work in the firm's branch offices in London and on the Continent, Lovett became aware of the threat posed to world peace by Hitler's rise to power. On his own initiative, Lovett toured aircraft plants in the United States and prepared a report emphasizing the need for rapid development of military aviation. The report came to the attention of Robert Patterson, then under secretary of the army, who, in 1940, named Lovett his special assistant.
Henry L. Stimson, the secretary of war, asked Lovett to assume the position of assistant secretary of war for air in April, 1941. In this post Lovett directed the growth of United States air power and gained for the air corps the semi-autonomous status which it held within the army throughout World War II. In September, 1945, Lovett received the Distinguished Service Medal, and in December, resigned from government service to resume his work with Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.
Lovett returned to Washington in 1947 when he was appointed under secretary of state by Secretary of State George C. Marshall, a post which he held until Marshall left the State Department in January, 1949. During the Korean War, Lovett once again held positions in the Truman administration, from 1950-1951 as deputy secretary of defense and from 1951-1953 as secretary of defense.
Resuming his business interests in New York in 1953, Lovett retained his concern for military affairs. He was appointed to several presidential commissions and testified before Congress. He also served on the boards of several foundations and charitable organizations. Lovett retired from the board of Union Pacific in 1976 and died at his home in Locust Valley, New York, on May 7, 1986.
Aeronautics -- History; Investment banking; United States -- Politics and government -- 1933-1953; Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971; Bush, Prescott Sheldon, 1895-1972; Carter, Marshall S. (Marshall Sylvester), 1909-1993; Davison, Frederick Trubee, 1896-1974; Eaker, Ira, 1896-1987; Forrestal, James, 1892-1949; Gates, Artemus L. (Artemus Lamb), 1895-1976; George, C. J. (Clarence James), 1916-1987; Hoffman, Anna Rosenberg, 1902-1983; Leva, Marx, 1915-; Lovett, Robert A. (Robert Abercrombie), 1895-1986; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989; Norstad, Lauris, 1907-1988; O'Hara, John, 1905-1970; Pogue, Forrest C.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Wallenburg, Marcus, 1899-; Abercrombie family; Lovett family; Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co; George C. Marshall Research Foundation
- Correspondence and Topical Files, 1919-1986; Series I; 12.25' (30 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The material in this series is filed by personal name, corporate name, or subject. File folders are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abercrombie family: genealogy, Circa 1920s-1930s, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Acheson, David, 1974, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1947, 1950-1971, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Air Force Aid Society, 1947-1954, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American-Scottish Foundation, Inc., 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Amherst College, 1959, 1964, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    General
    See also: box 31, folder 441
  - Amherst College: honorary degree, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    See also: box 34, folder 472
  - Autograph requests, 1974-1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aviation Commandery of the Naval Order of the United States, 1936, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Aviation history, 1925-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Aviation history: naval, 1966-1968, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Aviation history: Yale Unit, 1929, 1966-1967, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ba-Bl (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bo-Br (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bailey, Sydney, 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Barnett, Frank, 1973-1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Benton, William, 1949, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Berryman, James, 1953-1960, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bohlen, Charles, 1960, 1962, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Brookings Institution, 1957-1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brown, James: minutes in memory of, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bu-By (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co., 1920, 1938, 1946, 1971 undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.: books and albums, 1950, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.: daily log sheets and diary (microfilm from New York Historical Society), 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.: 150th anniversary, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.: "The Personality of a Bank", 1959, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Brown, Shipley & Co. Limited, 1926-1936, 1946-1963, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Brown University, 1952, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Brown University: honorary degree, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Bryce, Angele, 1933-1982 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Burden, William, 1967, 1972-1980 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Burt, William R., 1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Bush, Prescott, 1958-1973, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Butterworth, W. Walton, 1962-1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Ca-Coi (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Col-Cor (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Cr-Cu (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Cambridge Research Institute, 1970, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Canfield, Cass, 1958-1971, 1982, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Carter, Marshall N.; Carter, Marshall S.; Carter, Preot, 1949-1969 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Restricted (Box 35, Folder 478)
  - Carter, Marshall N.; Carter, Marshall S.; Carter, Preot, 1970-1986 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    See also: box 9, folders 101-103
  - Central Intelligence Group, 1946-1950 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Chilton family: genealogy, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Christman, Calvin L., 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Cigliani-Piazza, Giorgio, 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Clark, Charles, 1956, 1958, 1964-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Clark, W. Dale, 1950-1966, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Clifford, Clark, 1949-1953, 1960-1969, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Columbia University, 1949-1965, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Columbia University: honorary degree, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1949-1950, 1957, 1964-1970, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Coolidge, Charles A., 1953-1959, 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., 1937-1941, 1965-1973 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Coyne, J. Patrick, 1965, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Curtis, Louis, 1929-1930, 1950, 1953, 1958, 1963-1971, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Curtiss-Wright Corporation, 1943, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Dac-Day (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - De-Di (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Do-Du (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Davis Polk & Wardwell, 1933, 1946-1985 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Davison, F. Trubee, 1926-1940, 1949-1968, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - De Rothschild, Edmund, 1956-1963, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Disarmament, 1964, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Douglas, James, 1953, 1961-1965, 1978-1985 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Douglas, Lewis W., 1950, 1956-1969 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Dulles, John Foster
    See also: box 24, folder 329
  - E (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Eaker, Ira C., 1954-1968 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    See also: box 27, folder 375
    See also: box 34, folder 475
  - Eaker, Ira C., 1970-1985 (Box 7, Folder 71-73)
  - Early and Pioneer Naval Aviator's Association, 1966, 1971-1985 (Box 7, Folder 74-75)
  - Eaton, Frederick M., 1958-1964, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1950, 1963, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 77)
    See also: box 22, folder 293
  - Elliston, Herbert, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - English-Speaking Union, 1949-1954, 1962-1977 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Fa-Fi (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Fl-Fo (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Fr-Fu (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Fanton, Jonathan F., 1973-1984 (Box 8, Folder 83-84)
  - Finch, Henry A., 1932-1937, 1949, 1956, 1962-1966 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, 1950-1953, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Ford Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Forrestal, James V., 1940-1971, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    See also: box 8, folder 78
    See also: box 24, folder 327
  - Fosdick, Dorothy, 1967-1972, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Foundations: lists and taxation of, 1967-1982 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - France and DeGaulle, 1945, 1963, undated (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Fund for the Republic, Inc., 1958-1969 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Ga-Gi (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Gl-Go (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Gr-Gu (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Gates, Artemus L., 1929, 1937-1960, 1968, 1976, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Gay, Marie Lucie, 1949-1968 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Gemuseus, A. Walter, 1936-1937, 1949-1965, 1971, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - George C. Marshall Memorial Committee, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - George C. Marshall Research Foundation, 1964, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 100)
    See also: box 32, folder 448
  - George C. Marshall Research Foundation, 1981 April-1983 September (Box 9, Folder 101-103)
  - George C. Marshall Research Foundation, 1983 October-1986 (Box 10, Folder 104-108)
  - George C. Marshall Research Foundation: Lovett Reading Room dedication, 1981 March-May (Box 10, Folder 109)
    See also: box 33, folder 462
  - George C. Marshall Research Foundation: Lovett Reading Room dedication, 1981 June-1982 April (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - George, Clarence J., 1953-1966, 1980, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 111)
    See also: box 21, folder 268
  - German Marshall Fund of the United States, 1973-1974 March (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - German Marshall Fund of the United States, 1974 May-1981 (Box 11, Folder 113-114)
  - Ghormley Report, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - "Gilt-Edged Insecurity": correspondence relating to article, 1951-1966, 1978, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Goldberg, Alfred, 1974-1976, 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 117)
    See also: box 32, folder 459
  - Goodrich, Nathaniel H., 1956-1964 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Grand Cross of the Order of Leopold II, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Green, Murray, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - H (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Hadley, Arthur T., 1953, 1955, 1957-1964, 1967-1974, 1980-1981, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Hadley, Katherine B., 1955, 1961-1969, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Hallstein, Walter, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Hamilton, Fowler, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Hammond, Paul Y., 1956-1961 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Hanks, Stedman S., 1966-1972 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - Hansell, Haywood S., 1973, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Hardenbrook, Donald J., 1956 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Hardin, B. Lauriston, 1963-1966, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Harrar, George A., 1962-1968 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Harriman, E. H.: bust by Rodin, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Harriman, E. Roland, 1935-1941, 1946-1955, 1961-1967, 1973-1978, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - Harriman, W. Averell, 1973, 1979-1985 (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - Harriman Ripley & Co., 1938-1942, 1953, 1958, 1963, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - Harris, Huntington, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Harris, William R., 1962-1964 (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - Harry S. Truman Library, 1953-1985 (Box 12, Folder 138-139)
  - Harvard Business School Club of New York, 1955, 1965-1982 (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - Harvard Business School Fund, 1956, 1962-1980 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - Harvard Graduate Society for Advanced Study and Research, 1965-1973 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Harvard Law School, 1954, 1966-1972, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Harvard Law School Association, 1964-1983 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - Harvard Law School Fund, 1959-1980 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Harvard University, 1965-1971, 1976, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Harvard University: honorary degree, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Harvard University: Lovett-Learned Professorship, 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Harvard University. Graduate School of Business Administration, 1963-1986 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Hauge, Gabriel, 1961-1963 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Heath, Edward, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Heilbroner, Robert L., 1962 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - Heller, Robert, 1953-1963 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Henrickson, Alan K., 1980 (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - Henry L. Stimson memorial, 1960-1963 (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - Hermann, Charles F., 1966 (Box 13, Folder 156)
  - Higgins, Judith, 1977, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 157)
  - Hildt, Margaret, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 158)
  - Hill School, 1928, 1960-1980, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 159)
  - Hoch, Ernest T., 1962-1964, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 160)
  - Hoffman, Anna Rosenberg
    See also: box 25, folder 343
  - Hoffman, Martin R., 1976 (Box 13, Folder 161)
  - Hoffman, Paul G., 1956-1962, 1971-1976 (Box 13, Folder 162)
  - Holland, Henry F., 1958-1962 (Box 13, Folder 163)
  - Holland, Max, 1982-1984 (Box 13, Folder 164)
  - Honorary degrees: declined, 1951-1953, 1959-1964 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Houghton, Amory, 1973, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Houghton, James R., 1970-1977 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Hoxie, Gordan, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Hudson, Daryl, 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Hunter, Clarence E., 1964, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - I (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Iglehart, Joe A. W., 1970, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - International Chamber of Commerce, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - International Industrial Conference, 1968-1970 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Invitations regretted: Ae-Ge, 1977-1984 (Box 14, Folder 175)
  - Invitations regretted: Gi-Sm, 1977-1984 (Box 14, Folder 176)
  - Invitations regretted: So-Ye, 1977-1986 (Box 14, Folder 177)
  - Ireland, R. L., 1978-1979, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 178)
  - J (Box 14, Folder 179)
  - J. P. Morgan & Co., 1955-1959 (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - Jabsson Foundation, 1964-1971 (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - Jackson, Henry, 1963, 1970, 1981-1985 (Box 14, Folder 182)
    See also: box 8, folder 89
  - Jaffee, et. al. vs. U.S.A., et. al., U.S.D.C., D.N.J., C.I.V. No. 78-1014, 1978-1982 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - James Parton and Company, Inc., 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 184)
    See also: box 32, folder 458
    See also: box 33, folder 482
  - James Parton and Company, Inc., 1980-1984 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - Job seekers: Ac-K, 1961-1974 (Box 15, Folder 186)
  - Job seekers: M-W, 1961-1974 (Box 15, Folder 187)
  - John Fitzgerald Kennedy Library, 1964-1970 (Box 15, Folder 188)
  - John Fitzgerald Kennedy School of Government, 1966-1968 (Box 15, Folder 189)
    See also: box 24, folder 326
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1963-1965 (Box 15, Folder 190)
  - Ka-Ki (Box 15, Folder 191)
  - Kl-Ky (Box 15, Folder 192)
  - Kalicki, Jan H., 1970-1972 (Box 15, Folder 193)
  - Kelly, Mervin J., 1959 (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - Kennedy, Edward M., 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 195)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1962-1963 (Box 15, Folder 196)
  - Kennedy, Robert F., 1963-1968 (Box 15, Folder 197)
    See also: box 15, folder 188
  - Kent, Roger, 1953-1957 (Box 15, Folder 198)
  - Kirkpatrick, Lyman B., 1960-1965 (Box 15, Folder 199)
    See also: box 16, folder 211
  - Kreider, Joseph R., 1961-1965, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 200)
  - Krieger, Wolfgang, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 201)
  - Krock, Arthur, 1949, 1953, 1958-1973 (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - Kuter, Lawrence S., 1955, 1961-1962, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - La-Le (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - Li-Lo (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - Laidlaw, William R., 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 206)
  - Laird, Melvin R., 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 207)
  - Lamont, Thomas S., 1954-1966 (Box 16, Folder 208)
  - Lattimer, John K., 1959-1966, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 209)
  - Lawhler, Oscar T., 1960-1968, 1977-1980 (Box 16, Folder 210)
  - LeBoutiller, Phillip, 1954-1959 (Box 16, Folder 211)
  - Lee, Harold B., 1950, 1956, 1961-1970 (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - Leijonhufund, Erik, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 213)
  - Leva, Marx, 1953-1960, 1962-1964, 1970-1971, 1979, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 214-215)
  - Lieberson, Goddard, 1956, 1958, 1972-1975, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 216)
  - Litton Industries, Inc., 1956-1971 (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - London Corporation Agreement, 1936-1938 (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Long Island University, 1962-1966 (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - Long Island University: honorary degree, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 220)
  - Lovett, Adele Brown: passports, travel notes, 1927, 1950-1955, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 221)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: address book, undated (Box 16, Folder 222)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: biographies, 1951, 1986, undated (Box 16, Folder 223)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: certificates and citations, 1919, 1949, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 224)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: congratulatory messages on appointment as deputy secretary of defense, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 225)